A Finding Aid to the Chester Beach Papers, 1846-1999, bulk circa 1900-1999, in the Archives of American Art AAA.beacches
Archives of American Art
Chester Beach papers
bulk 1895-1999
1846-1999
AAA.beacches
Archives of American Art
7.3 Linear feet
The Chester Beach papers measure 7.3 linear feet and are dated 1846-1999, bulk circa 1900-1999. The work and professional activities of Beaux Arts sculptor Chester Beach (1881-1956) and his family's efforts to exhibit and sell work from the estate are documented by project files, business records, correspondence, scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs. The papers also include many artist-designed Christmas cards sent and received by the Beach family, and artwork by Chester Beach and others.
Beach, Chester
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Chester Beach papers were donated in 2009 by the estate of Eleanor Beach Fitchen, Chester Beach's daughter, through her grandson and executor, John Fitchen.
Separated Materials note
Portions of the Chester Beach papers were loaned by Eleanor Beach Fitchen in 1967 and 1968 for microfilming on reels N727-N729 and N68-11; some of these papers were not included in the 2009 gift and are still available on microfilm and for interlibrary loan. The loaned materials are not described in the container listing of this finding aid but include passports, genealogical materials, photograph albums, travel sketches, travel diaries of Mrs. Beach, and business and family correspondence. Loaned obituary letters on reel N68-11 are also referenced in a scrapbook in Series 8.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original material requires an appointment. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Biographical/Historical note
Sculptor Chester Beach (1881-1956) was known for portrait busts, allegorical and mythological figures, coins and medallic art in the Beaux-Arts tradition. He lived and worked in New York City and Brewster, New York.
Chester Beach, son of Chilion Beach and Elizabeth Ferris Beach, was born in San Francisco on May 23, 1881. Beach initially studied at the California School of Mechanical Arts in 1899. He remained in San Francisco and between 1900 and 1902 continued his art training at the Mark Hopkins Institute of Art while working as a jewelry designer. To further his career and exposure to artistic trends, Beach moved to New York City in 1903. The following year, he went to Paris, enrolled at the Ecole des Beaux-Arts, and also studied with Raoul Verlet at the Académie Julian.
Upon his return to New York in 1907, Beach established a studio on Tenth Street. He won the National Academy of Design's Barnett Prize for sculpture in 1907 and the Academy elected him an Associate Artist the following year. His increased stature resulted in numerous portrait commissions and eventually lead to commissions for monuments and architectural sculpture. In 1910, Chester Beach married Eleanor Hollis Murdock, a painter he met when both were art students in Paris. The couple spent the next two years in Rome; for several years and after returning Beach continued to spend time in Italy and maintained a studio in Rome.
Solo exhibitions of Beach's work were presented at Macbeth Gallery (1912), Pratt Institute (1913), Cincinnati Art Museum (1916), John Herron Art Institute (1916), and Memorial Art Gallery, Rochester (1917). In addition to frequent participation in annual exhibitions at the National Academy of Design and the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, Beach was represented in the Panama-Pacific International Exposition (1915), and in group shows at venues including: Art Institute of Chicago, Boston Art Club, California Palace of the Legion of Honor, and National Arts Club.
The gold medal presented by Académie Julian (1905), Beach's first award, was followed by many other prizes, among them: American Numismatic Society prize for a medal commemorating the Peace of Versailles (1919) and its Saltus Medal for distinguished medallic art (1946); Architectural League of New York gold medal (1924); National Academy of Design Barnett Prize (1907) and Watrous gold medal (1926); National Arts Club medal and prizes (1923, 1926, 1932); and the Panama-Pacific International Exposition silver medal (1915).
Beach was an Academician of the National Academy of Design, a member of the American Numismatic Society, Architectural League of New York, National Arts Club, National Institute of Arts and Letters, and the National Sculpture Society (President, 1927-1928).
For more than 40 years, Beach lived and worked at 207 East 17th Street. The brownstone, purchased in 1913, was large enough for the family's home, his studio, and additional studios that were rented to other artists. Through barter, Beach acquired land in Brewster, NY, and in 1917 hired Italian stonemasons to build a studio. Later, they erected a summer house for the family. Many old stone walls on the site provided material for both buildings and Beach named the property Oldwalls.
After a long illness, Chester Beach died at Oldwalls on August 6, 1956. The funeral service was held at his Brewster, NY, studio and he is buried in Cold Spring Cemetery, Cold Spring, NY.
Scope and Contents note
The Chester Beach papers measure 7.3 linear feet and are dated 1846-1999, bulk circa 1900-1999. The work and professional activities of Beaux Arts sculptor Chester Beach (1881-1956) and his family's efforts to exhibit and sell work from the estate are documented by project files, business records, correspondence, scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs. The papers also include many artist-designed Christmas cards sent and received by the Beach family, and artwork by Chester Beach and others.
Biographical material consists of biographical notes, identification cards and a membership certificate.
Project files contain correspondence, financial records, notes, drawings and plans, research materials, printed matter, and photographs that document commissions for sculpture, medals and coins, monuments, and Beach's own projects. Among the most thoroughly documented projects are a fountain sculpture for the grounds of the Cleveland Museum of Art ( Sun, Earth, Fountain of the Waters, and Zodiac) and the Edward W. Bok Memorial in Mountain Lake, Florida; both commissions were executed in conjunction with the firm of Frederick Law Olmsted.
Business records include Chester Beach's general business correspondence and correspondence concerning consignments. An address book records names, addresses, and occasionally indicates prices of services and supplies used by the sculptor. Other record books detail expenses and income of the studio building Beach owned,with a list of the effects of the former owner, sculptor William Couper; bronzes cast; sales, with titles, prices, and buyers; and names and addresses of clients, dealers, and suppliers; and instructions for cleaning and bronzing plaster.
Family correspondence consists mainly of letters, many mentioning Chester Beach, addressed to Mrs. Chester Beach and daughter Eleanor Beach Fitchen. Estate correspondence and related documents concern efforts to exhibit, sell, and research Beach's remaining work. These records, for the most part, were created by Mrs. Fitchen who acted as sales agent, ran the Chester Beach Memorial Studio, and maintained the Beach archive. Of particular interest is a series of letters from Brenda Kuhn that relate what she learned from handling the estate of her father, Walt Kuhn; in addition, she offered ideas and advice about exhibitions, the Memorial Studio, and the Beach Centennial.
Beach designed his family's annual Christmas cards, most of which incorporate images of their three daughters. A complete set, preserved in an album, includes a few later cards that reproduce artwork by his widow. Many of the cards received - some with original artwork - are from artist friends, among them: Ernest Blumenschein, Edward W. Greacen, Hazel Brill Jackson, Paul Jennewein, Bonnie Leibig, F. Luis Mora, Robert Nisbet, and Ezra Winter. Also of note are a card from Walker Hancock bearing a photograph of his studio; a painting of Beach's Sylvan at Brookgreen Gardens, reproduced on Anna Hyatt Huntington's card; and a card from Beach patron Mary Jester Allen containing a brief note about the Frontier Art Colony she had established near Cody, Wyoming.
Among the drawings and sketches by Chester Beach are student work, designs for some of his Christmas cards, and a sketchbook containing drawings of sculpture. Work by other artists consists of prints, including one by Ezra Winter.
Three scrapbooks, largely comprised of newspaper clipping and other printed material, contain a variety of other items, including: Letters from the American Academy in Rome, Architectural League of New York, Ecole des Beaux Arts, Daniel Chester French, Hazel Brill Jackson, Frederick MacMonnies, National Academy of Design, National Sculpture Society, Jessica B. Piexotto, and Salon d'Autome. Awards and certificates from the National Academy of Design, Panama-Pacific International Exposition. Bookplates and a place card Beach etched for Mr. and Mrs. George Davison; and an unfinished poem by FitzRoy Carrington. Photographs are of a night school class Beach attended at the Mark Hopkins Art Institute in San Francisco, Beach at work in his studio, and a portrait of him painted by G. Laurance Nelson.
Printed material includes Panama-Pacific International Exposition guide books, brochures about the Chester Beach Memorial Studio in Brewster, NY, and catalogs for solo and group exhibitions.
Photographs of artwork are mainly of Chester Beach's sculpture and include views of work in progress. Also found are photographs of drawings and sculpture from his student years in California and Paris. Pictures of work by other artists are portraits of Chester Beach painted by G. Laurance Nelson and by his daughter, Natalie Beach McLaury. Among the photographs of Chester Beach are several by Gertrude Kasebier, circa 1910. Other pictures show Beach in his studio, Beach with family and friends, and a "Dinner tendered to Edmund W. Greacen by Samuel T. Shaw, Salmagundi Club, March 2, 1922." Places documented are Beach's boyhood home in San Francisco, the interiors of his studios, and Brookgreen Gardens. Miscellaneous subjects are nude models.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 10 series. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1910-1947 (Box 1; 4 folders)
Series 2: Project Files, 1846-1999 (Boxes 1-2, 11, OV 12-13; 1.6 linear ft.)
Series 3: Business Records, circa 1900-1958 (Box 2; 0.4 linear ft.)
Series 4: Writings, 1913-1935 (Box 3; 2 folders)
Series 5: Correspondence, 1875, 1933-1996 (Box 3; 0.5 linear ft.)
Series 6: Christmas Cards, 1909-1961 (Boxes 3-4; 0.7 linear ft.)
Series 7: Artwork, circa 1900-1955 (Boxes 4, 11; 0.3 linear ft.)
Series 8: Scrapbooks, 1903-1972 (Box 10; 0.3 linear ft.)
Series 9: Printed Material, 1910-1997 (Box 4; 0.4 linear ft.)
Series 10: Photographs, circa 1885-circa 1960s (Boxes 4-9, 11, 14; 3.1 linear ft.)
Allen, Mary Jester; American Academy in Rome; Architectural League of New York; Beach, Eleanor Murdock; Blumenschein, Ernest Leonard, 1874-1960; Carrington, Fitz Roy, 1869-1954; Couper, William, 1853-1942; Ecole nationale supèrieure des beaux-arts (France); Fitchen, Eleanor Beach; French, Daniel Chester, 1850-1931; Greacen, Edmund W., 1876-1949; Hancock, Walker Kirtland, 1901-; Jackson, Hazel Brill; Jennewein, Carl Paul, 1890-; Kuhn, Brenda, 1911-; Kuhn, Walt, 1877-1949; Leibig, Bonnie; MacMonnies, Frederik William, 1863-1937; Mark Hopkins Institute of Art; Mora, F. Luis (Francis Luis), 1874-1940; National Academy of Design (U.S.); National Sculpture Society (U.S.); Nelson, Laurence, 1887-1978; Nisbet, Robert H., 1879-1961; Olmsted, Frederick Law, 1822-1903; Panama-Pacific International Exposition (1915: San Francisco, Calif.); Salmagundi Club; Winter, Ezra, 1886-1949; Artists' studios; Christmas cards; Drawings; Eclecticism in architecture; Photographs; Poems; Prints; Scrapbooks; Sculptors -- New York (State)--New York; Sculptors, American--New York (State)--New York; Sculpture--Economic aspects; Sculpture--Equipment and supplies; Sculpture--Technique; Sketchbooks; Sketches
- Biographical Material, 1910-1947; Series 1; 4 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  The legal document concerns a piano-forte - a wedding gift Thomas Leeming shipped to the Beaches in Rome - that would return to New York with them. The membership certificate is from the National Institute of Arts and Letters.
  Arrangement note
  Scrapbooks (Series 8) contain additional biographical material, including: exhibitors' cards, certificates of award from the Panama-Pacific International Exposition and The Architectural League of New York, and a certificate of election as Academician of the National Academy of Design.
  - Biographical Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Insurance and Social Security Cards, 1947; undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Legal Document, U. S. Consulate in Rome, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership Certificate, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Project Files, 1846-1999; Series 2; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 1-2, 11, OV 12-13
  Project files document commissions and a few proposals for commissions not awarded, as well as Beach's own projects. The files - some sparse, and others extremely detailed - may include correspondence, financial records, notes, drawings, printed material, and photographs. Photographs are mainly of completed sculpture, but many files also contain views of maquettes, work in progress, and pictures of sitters. Found less frequently are site photographs and pictures of events such as unveilings and dedication ceremonies.
  Sun and Earth, Fountain of the Waters, and Zodiac produced for the Fine Art Gardens of the Cleveland Museum of Art, and the Edward W. Bok Memorial in Mountain Lake, Florida, are among Beach's most extensively documented commissions. These projects were done in conjunction with Frederick Law Olmsted, and their respective files contain correspondence with Olmsted and members of his firm.
  Other well-documented projects of note are: Riders of the Elements, commissioned for the 1939 New York World's Fair; Brewster (NY) Civil War Monument, Crosby Post #302, with documentation of its late 20th century restoration; six busts commissioned for the Hall of Fame for Great Americans, 1924-1932; and portrait busts, President William Henry Harrison for the Virginia State Capitol and Senator Oscar W. Underwood for the United States Capitol. The project file for The Legend of Archmere contains numerous finished drawings.
  Nineteenth century items consist of a few publications and prints used as reference sources for portraits. Posthumous material in these files was added by Eleanor Beach Fitchen who ran the Chester Beach Memorial Studio, acted as the estate's sales agent, and maintained her father's archive.
  - Alderfer - Jacob Franklin Alderfer, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A.T. and T. - Service to the Nation in War and Peace (bronze and marble), undated; 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Oversized material housed in OV 13
  - Babbott (Box 1)
    - Dr. Frank Babbott (bronze, 1933); Family hands (bronze), 1933-1934; undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Lydia Babbott (ivory and 4 bronzes, 1931), undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - A Bacchante (marble, 1910?), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bacchus and Faun (bronze, 1908), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Beach (Box 1)
    See also: Toto [daughter Eleanor], Box 2, folder 47
    - Beata Beach (terra cotta), undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - My Wife, Eleanor (marble), 1914-1915; undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Beyond (marble, 1920), 1996; undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Big Wave (bronze, 1913), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bok - Edward W. Bok Memorial (Mountain Lake, Florida, 1928) (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, Financial Records, 1927-1931 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Notes, Drawings, Printed Material, Photographs, 1927-1959; undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Oversized material housed in OV 12
  - Boy with Boat (ivory, 1920), 1965-1966; undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Boy with Pipes (bronze, 1918), 1920; undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Breath of the Pines (bronze, 1906-1907), undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Brewster Civil War Monument, Crosby Post #302 (bronze and marble, 1933) (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, Working Sketches, Printed Material, undated; 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Restoration, 1997-1998; undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Photographs, 1997-1998; undated; circa 1933 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Brown (Box 1)
    - Gordon Brown Memorial (marble, 1914), undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - John Crosby Brown Memorial (bronze, 1910), undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Brunn - Freda M. Brunn Memorial (bronze, 1909-1910), undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Buffalo Bill Half Dollar (not produced), 1936 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Chalmers - Ann Chalmers (terra cotta), 1941; undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Cleveland Museum of Art (Box 1)
    See also: Box 2, F 39 and Box 2, F 70
    - Correspondence, 1926-1928; undated; 3 Folders (Box 1, Folder 28-30)
    - Notes; Drawing; Plan; Printed Material, circa 1926-1938 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Photographs (Box 1)
      - Completed Sculpture, circa 1927-1928; 1963-1998 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Models and Construction, circa 1926-1928 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Site, circa 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Dedication Ceremony, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Cloud (marble, 1912), undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Cooper - Peter Cooper (Hall of Fame for Great Americans, New York; bronze, 1924, undated) (Box 1, Folder 37)
    See: Box 1, F 62
  - Crane Fountain (Hathaway Brown School, Cleveland; bronze, 1930), undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Crowing, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Crying (terra cotta, 1915), undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Davison (Box 1)
    - George W. Davison (bronze, 1910), undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Harriet Davison (marble, 1913), undated; 1912-1942 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Robert and Alfred Davison (Wesleyan College Infirmary; marble, 1935), undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Dawn - Evening; Dawn - Youth and Age; Head of Dawn (marble, 1918), undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - De Silver - Harrison De Silver, One Year (marble, 1915), undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - De Vinne - Louis De Vinne (bronze, 1926), undated; 1912-1936 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Doherty - Henry L. Doherty, 1932-1942, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Echo of Greece (ivory, bronze), undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Elliot - Professor Elliot (bronze, 1918), undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Emmons - George E. Emmons (General Electric Co.; bronze, 1925) (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - First Born (marble, 1912), undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Fish Fountain (cement, 1922?), undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Fitchen - Douglas Beach Fitchen, Ellen Elizabeth Fitchen, and Anne W. Fitchen [Beach grandchildren], undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Fountain Figure, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Fountain of the Waters (The Cleveland Museum of Art; marble, 1926-1928), undated; Box 2, F 39 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Gates - Dorothy Gates, Ten Days Old, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Glint of the Sea (bronze, 1924), 1928 - 1965; undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Grant - Madison Grant (bronze, circa 1919-1920) (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Gray (Box 1)
    - Asa Gray (Hall of Fame for Great Americans, New York; bronze, 1925), undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
      See: Box 1, F 63
    - William S. Gray (bronze, 1925?), undated; 1935-1968 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Great Grandmother (marble), undated; 1946 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Hall of Fame for Great Americans, New York (Box 1)
    - Peter Cooper (bronze, 1924), undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Asa Gray (bronze, 1925), undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - George Mason (marble, 1932), undated; 1932-1937 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Samuel F. B. Morse (bronze, 1928), undated; 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Walt Whitman (bronze, 1931), 1931 - 1938; undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Eli Whitney (bronze, 1926), 1846-1926; undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Haney - James Parton Haney Memorial (bronze, 1925), 1917-1925; undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Harrison - President William Henry Harrison (Virginia State Capitol; bronze, 1931) (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1931; undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Drawings, Printed Material, Photographs, 1931-1946; undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
      Oversized material housed in Box 11
  - Head of Legato and Fragment (marble, 1910?), 1912; undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Herrara - General Herrara (1911), undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Herter - Christian Herter (bronze, 1911 and 1913), undated; (oversized material housed in Box 11) (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Holt - Dr. Luther E. Holt Memorial Tablet (Babies' Hospital; marble, 1930), 1928-1930; undated (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Humanity in Industry, Maskell Ewing Fox, Sr., Cephas Brainerd Fox, Louis Vultee Fox, Maskell Ewing Fox, Jr. (M. Ewing Fox Co.; bronze, 1932), undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Ideals/The Artist's Vision/The Inexpressible, undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Jacobs - Charles M. Jacobs (marble, 1908), undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Johnson - Constantine Johnson (terra cotta bust and figure, 1916), undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Julliard - Augustus D. Julliard (bronze), 1924-1925; undated (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Key - Francis Scott Key, undated (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Ladd - Anthony Ladd (terra cotta, 1931); Frances Ladd (bronze), 1970; 1923; undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Leaping Spray, 1929; undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Leeming - Helen Leeming (marble, 1909), 1971-1973; undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Legend of Archmere, 1916; undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Lewisohn - Adolph Lewisohn (bronze, 1926), undated; 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - MacDonald, Helen - Medallion of Child (bronze and 2 ivory reductions), 1932; undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Mason - George Mason (Hall of Fame for Great Americans, NY; marble, 1932), undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    See: Box 1, F 64
  - Mermaid, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Miller, Marilyn (Mrs. Jack Pickford) - Ivory figurine, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mora - Rosemary Mora, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Morse - Samuel F. B. Morse (Hall of Fame for Great Americans, NY; bronze, 1928), 1927-1928; undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    See: Box 1, F 65
  - New York Edison Co. Relief commemorating "fifty years of New York Edison Co. service to New York City in home and industry" (bronze, 1932), undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Olcott - Jean Olcott (marble, 1913), undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Oregon Trail Memorial Half Dollar [commission awarded to James Earle Fraser and Laura Gardin Fraser], 1926-1929 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Panama-Pacific Exposition - 1 group and 2 figures (plaster), undated; 1915-1916 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Perry (Box 2)
    - Mrs. Thomas Perry (marble, 1943), 1942-1943; undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Perry Tombstone (marble), 1914 - 1923 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Purves - Mrs. Austin M. Purves (marble, 1909), undated; 1907-1918 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Resor - Stanley Resor (bronze, 1933), undated; 1933-1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Riders of the Elements (New York World's Fair) (Box 2)
    - Description of Group, Sketches, Correspondence, Contract, undated; 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Construction, Publicity, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Oversized materials housed in OV 12
    - Photographs, undated; circa 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Rising Sea Mists, 1926-1927; undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Robinson - Professor Robinson (University of Kansas; bronze, 1917) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Sacred Fire (marble, 1921), undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Scallop Fountain, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Scott - Mrs. Donald Scott and Sons (bronze, 1917), undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Sea Horses (bronze, 1924), undated (Box 2, Folder 28)